



About

Hi! My name is Inês (Portuguese pronunciation: i'neʃ). I'm 28 years old and live in London, UK. I moved here in early 2019 for work.

I have a bachelor in Informatics Engineering by the University of Coimbra and have been working as a software developer for a few years now.

My hobbies include reading and playing Minecraft. I also enjoy listening to the occasional podcast (Soft Skills Engineering and No Such Thing As A Fish being my favorites at the moment).

At the end of 2020 I decided to add learning French and React to the list - my website is a result of the latter. So far it has allowed me to learn about React, CSS and Flexbox, and GitHub Actions. You can find the code on my GitHub account.

I'm always looking for interesting opportunities, so feel free to say hi!



J +44 7761 824051 (UK) / +351 935 889 881 (PT)

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Informatics Engineering at the University of Coimbra

O Sep 2012 to Aug 2017

• Coimbra, Portugal

Experience

Product Lead for Ethics Monitor at Haplo

O May 2019 to January 2021

• London, United Kingdom

Product lead for Ethics Monitor, which helps universities streamline the review of applications for ethical approval.

All products and client specific customisations were implemented as server-side JavaScript plugins, using Haplo's framework API.

During my time at Haplo I:

- Worked closely with new clients throughout the process of building their custom application, from authentication setup to deployment.
- Provided support for existing clients.
- Mentored a colleague working on the same product.
- Worked alongside my colleagues to improve the product.
- Contributed to weekly discussions on the teams' challenges and how to improve the way we worked.



JavaScript

Software Developer at HYP

O Sep 2018 to Jan 2019

♥ Coimbra, Portugal

At HYP, I worked with a small team of developers and designers to develop BabyLoop, a platform to buy and sell used baby products (such as cribs, car seats, etc).

My responsabilities included (but where not limited to):

- Building several components of the website, including search and product pages.
- Creating an API to be consumed by the mobile app, using Ruby on Rails API.
- Building the payments' process (using the SIBS API) as well as invoice generation (using the InvoiceExpress API).
- Configuring emails and the jobs to send them, using Rails' Active Jobs.
- Building an admin back office, to manage the content of the platform, using rails_admin.



Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, Postman

Junior Ruby Developer at OneSource

O Mar 2017 to Aug 2018

🕈 Coimbra, Portugal

At OneSource, I was tasked with developing an extension for SketchUp to optimize the structure of any building designed by the user using the program. This was done using SketchUp's Ruby API and in collaboration with a team of civil engineers from the University of Coimbra.

As the only developer on the team, I was responsible for meetings with the client as well as reviewing and merging the code created by the civil engineers' team, making sure it worked seamlessly with the general extension code.

The extension ran as a script inside SketchUp's Ruby environment. I developed the HTML and CSS, as well as the backend of the app (which dealt with calculations, interaction with the database, API calls, etc). Authentication and database download/update were made using AJAX requests to OneSource's servers, where the information was stored.

P GitHub

Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Postman

Ruby on Rails Internship at HYP

O Jul 2016 to Sep 2016

♥ Coimbra, Portugal

Web application to pick movies to watch with friends, based on which movies everyone on the group wants to watch.

း GitLab

Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery

Skills

Programming

 Javascript
 ★★★☆

 Ruby
 ★★★☆

 Ruby on Rails
 ★★★☆

 React
 ★★☆☆

 Redux
 ★☆☆☆

HTML CSS Java Python



Git

Operating Systems

Languages